A face. a fleet. a war. a man. a thought. a dream. a dream. a dream. a dream. a dream.
A trick.
A trick to break the walls of Troy.
And burn it. screaming to the ground.
I don't know what's going on. but I don't know what to do.
What does it mean?
A gift...
for Athena.
Common gods...
respect their offering.
Save her from the waves.
Take her to Athena's temple.
The war is over.
Stop!
Not this song.
I want to remind them of who's wine they're drinking.
I don't want Odysseus' song. I want Odysseus.
Then why do you entertain suitors in his house night after night?
In this world. a man does what he chooses.
I do what I can.
I am a man now. Mom.
So throw them out.
Break Zeus' law and see what they do to you
if you give them that excuse.
I'm sorry.
I've already lost a husband.
I don't want to lose a son.
Dad's coming back.
And where is he?
Eight years.
Since Troy fell. almost 20. since he left us. where is he?
We have to welcome him like we welcomed all of you.
Are you calling us beggars?
I'm saying you've been welcome here for three years.
We've only enjoyed your hospitality for so long.
Because your mother won't choose.
She's already married.
Odysseus is dead.
What do you know about my dad?
You know he kept stringing cattle at the bad wine.
You had the best of it the first two seasons.
And I know he never came home.
Not yet.
You're pining for a daddy you didn't even know.
Like some sniffling bastard.
Well. since none of us can really know who our fathers are.
don't clean it online.
But I did know him.
As boys.
We watched him hunt.
I tried to volunteer for his expedition to Troy.
but he told me to stay here and keep an eye on you.
Only you're my mother.
You can't blame me for looking.
My dad is coming home.
and his hospitality won't be as generous as hers.
So he doesn't follow Zeus' law. then?
Zeus' law tells us to treat strangers
as we'd be treated because they might be gods in disguise.
I think we've established. Antinous.
that you are not a god.
This one certainly doesn't smell like a god.
Wouldn't be much of a disguise if he did.
Careful.
He might strike you down right now.
The thunder was luck I don't know you have wise eyes
seen his eyes here you see how the traders from Sparta
Has Menelaus come home from the war?
Years ago.
Odysseus never came back?
We don't even know if he's alive.
Have you heard anything?
The song of how he won the war.
We've all heard that.
Anything else?
No.
But Sparta is full of Trojan war veterans.
Someone will know something.
You know Odysseus' son?
Go to Sparta.
Go.
See Menelaus.
He'd welcome you.
The Queen wants to speak to the stranger.
She lives for news.
Just don't try to give her any false hope.
She has some way of knowing whether a person has actually seen Odysseus.
You see that man?
He can't see much anymore. but that doesn't stop him beating travelers to death
in exchange for lies about my father.
No. no. too fast.
How can you know?
You don't need eyes to hear a hasty combination.
Mentor. push him.
Uh!
He's friendly as you.
He only answered to you. Father.
Where'd he get him from?
He met right here.
I'll take him.
For your boy?
For a hunting dog.
Damned if he wasn't right.
Let's go.
Hold still. How bad a scar do you want?
Why do you always pluck your bow?
It's only fair.
To warn your prey?
To fight with honor.
You weren't fighting. you were hunting.
Hunting's nothing but fighting with stealth.
Clever. Clever. but your cleverness is going to get you in trouble.
Try again. This time not as fast or precise.
You can't win with a perfect defense.
Draw the attack.
How?
Hesitate. Open your belly to your opponent's blade.
Their attack becomes your chance.
Uh!
Cut a couple down. the others cave. bullies and cowards.
Most of them were old enough to go to Troy.
but when they saw Agamemnon's sail...
their fathers hid them.
And you knew Agamemnon's war would take
many years and many lives.
So he raised his army by lottery.
Name?
Sinon.
Draw.
No.
Name?
Antinous.
Draw.
Yes.
By lots?
Antinous told me he volunteered.
We've got to do something.
Your boy's trying to take Sinan's place.
I'm not going to let him.
He needs to stay here and take care of his family.
You can watch over your boy. too.
Of course.
He's with me.
What he wanted. Antinous. was to look after me.
No. no. no.
But Odysseus was sensitive to a father's shame.
He fell for these fathers.
You and your mother meant more to him
than promises of glory.
So he knew it would be years.
Did he tell my mother?
That's a question for her.
You may ask. is he ever coming back?
Hargis thinks so.
Never known a dog reached 20.
But he's long outlived his master.
I didn't mean to stop you.
I'm in no hurry.
The elders decreed when I finished
your grandfather's burial shroud.
it'll be time to remarry.
Why?
Ithaca's been without a king too long.
They want security.
From what?
People from the sea.
That's just travelers' tales.
All we know of the world is travelers' tales.
That's how we found out Troy and Bolan.
Now they all tell stories of attacks
by people from the sea.
And who are the people from the sea?
No one knows. but the elders wanted
they could be prepared.
Prepared?
Part of the greatest civilization ever known.
Look at this great house.
Stones as old as knowledge.
At the mercy of some greedy. unwanted guests.
The structure's nothing
without people's respect for its meaning.
Zeus' law.
To treat others as you would be treated.
When they abuse that. they destroy everything.
So how could you think of marrying one of them?
Because a long time ago.
your father asked me to.
Hagamemnon is our king.
The Trojans took his brother's wife.
Before she ran away with them.
Either way. the walls of Troy are said to be impregnable.
We'll sit outside that great city
trying to draw them into battle.
As the years go by. the Telemachus grows.
and you learn life without me.
Menelaus will give up on Helen.
This is Agamemnon's excuse
to break Troy's control of the trading routes.
He won't let it pass.
Ever.
Oh. what if you refuse?
He'll take our son.
He would never.
He sacrificed his own daughter for favorable wins.
What happens when God swans his daughter's life?
The power of a sacrifice
is in the cost to the person making it.
It's monstrous.
And committed.
I won't return soon.
If at all.
What if we ran?
took you fast to the ship and brightest crew
and headed for the horizon.
held hands on deck as we rode west at dusk.
chasing the escaping sun.
There's a world beyond these walls.
I commend on some vengeance.
but fall on all that I've got.
I promise me. if I don't return by the time Telemachus comes of age. promise me. you'll
take another husband. enough sacrifice.
Love's not a sacrifice.
Of course it is.
I don't want you to make it.
It's not up to you.
You promise me?
No.
Promise me you'll come back.
What if I can't?
Then your memory won't be making my decisions.
I think my men wear it always.
Athena will bring you home.
I'm not sure it suits me.
When travelers claim to have seen you.
I'll ask where you are wearing.
and I'll know if they're alive.
If the people from the sea are real.
right now. Ithaca has no king or he has an army.
I could take this room.
Come.
This is Drayton.
That's not fair.
You said only he could string this bow.
He was happy to let others try.
I need to line up all the axes.
Yeah.
No one else ever did it.
Mom. they're bleeding us dry. so you'll be forced to choose one of them before I can
claim the throne myself.
The Traveler told me Menelaus returned years ago.
They've all returned.
All who survived.
Maybe he is dead.
And if he is. then this is my palace.
We need to know.
I have to go to Menelaus to find out the truth.
Don't let me. because these suitors mean you harm.
Oh. you think I don't know that?
Every night they push me to give them the excuse they need.
I'm out there on the sea. on the road.
They want me an excuse. You just won't come back.
You don't want me to claim the throne myself.
You just want to keep me in my place
so that you can stay queen of Ithaca.
I've had enough of being queen of Ithaca without my king!
Without your king?
Or a king?
And you think you're ready to take your father's place?
Your child.
Too loud. Melanthius.
Don't wear your spurs in the palace.
You're a cowherd. not a horseman.
And you're a pig farmer.
And who are you to talk to me like that?
A servant our master left in charge of his herdsmen.
The master is long gone. you blind old fool.
And you're about as welcome here as that dog is.
No!
Argus!
Argus. say. he didn't do anything.
So that stink is you?
Leave the old dog alone.
Which one?
Both of us.
What did you say to me. slave?
He just got carried away.
Argus is my father's hunting dog.
His hunting dog?
Hey!
Look at that thing.
Get it out of here. but try not to eat it.
Don't. can't you see he's in pain?
Okay. then I'll put it out of his misbe-
Leave him alone!
Did you see?
You all see?
He attacked me!
I have the right!
Please!
Please don't hurt my son.
Easy. easy.
Young pup lost his head.
Show some mercy.
Drink some more of his wine. I'll take care of this.
It's my father's hunting dog.
He's only living to see Odysseus return.
That's fine.
I'll put him on the dung-heap out front
so he can greet his master a little sooner.
That dog stays out there.
Next time. think twice before you offer up your life for an animal.
You're clear.
Prepare supplies. Take them down to the ships.
Tell no one. Use only people you trust.
You've pricked your mother's heart.
If I stay. they'll force me to fight.
No one will back me.
I have to find out what happened to my father.
Ithaca will be behind me if they know Odysseus is dead.
His suitors will never know that.
You will never make it back. I'll have to...
Tell Lintor to meet me at the ships just before dawn.
What do you want me to tell your mother?
You have to hold out for as long as you can.
The ship's ready. The tide's red.
Have I ever told you that you have wise eyes?
Athena's eyes?
Once or twice.
You haven't even asked me where we're going yet.
Where are we going?
We'll find my dad. He's alive.
I can feel it in the wind and the waves.
He's out there somewhere. wandering. injured. lost.
I don't know.
But he's alive.
I don't know what to do.
More dreams?
Men drowning...
inside...
some...
dark space.
Firelight on stone. I don't know.
Don't you want to remember?
Why can't God speak in ways we understand?
Who doesn't understand thunder?
The fire.
A child's smile. a good harvest.
You hide yourselves from us.
Look.
Who's moving that cloud?
Massing those birds?
Who's moving the water?
What were you talking to?
Athena came to me again.
She's telling me to remember.
To leave.
Why would you leave?
We have everything we need.
How long have I been here. Calypso?
I have a home somewhere.
There's someone out there.
How do you know?
I don't know.
I feel.
What we have here could last forever.
Forever is for gods.
For you. a god.
You want to remember. but what if remembering destroys your happiness?
Then it wasn't real.
No. No more.
But I love it.
Stop eating the lotus.
Tell me what you remember.
After Troy.
Troy?
We won the war.
And then what?
What are you going to do?
Ten years on this fucking beach.
Let's go home.
Remember who we leave here.
Do we have enough provisions?
We've taken enough from Troy.
Another stop or two won't kill us.
And pull!
And...
Stow the oars.
Risk!
Stow the oars!
We'll raise the sail. Follow the southerly winds.
Yes. sir.
Agamemnon's rowing west on the known provisions route.
He's got more mouths to feed.
We'll find places to land.
Are you sure it's a risk?
unfollowed Agamemnon long enough.
With a little luck and the right winds.
we'll see some of the world
still be home before Agamemnon.
Come on. boys!
I don't know what's going on. but I think it's time to get out of here.
Just keep the bear on the right.
Oh. this is it! Land!
See? Lucky bastard.
We're down to our last supplies.
Assemble the landing party. Food and water.
Enough for three weeks.
What if they won't give it?
How badly do you want to get home?
Get your weapons ready!
Aging.
Move it!
Borrowing.
Ponder him.
Ask him why they abandoned their village
instead of welcoming us.
This says they thought we were the sea people.
No.
We're Greeks from Ithaca.
Maybe you heard our victory at Troy.
We're headed west on the southerly winds.
He says. if we go that way. we won't like the things we'll find.
After years of war. no one could stand between my men and home.
Not even me.
Did something happen?
I'm chasing the escaping sun.
Lance!
There you go.
Lucky bastard.
No. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no
I don't know what you're talking about.
Someone lives here.
Yeah. they make cheese.
It's pretty good. there's a lot of it.
We should leave. we've brought nothing to trade with.
Zeus' law.
I don't know if whoever lives here has heard of Zeus' law.
Or Zeus. for that matter.
Everyone's heard of Zeus' law.
Get the fire going.
We'll welcome the owner back.
Get away from the fire.
No!
Spill out!
I don't know what's going on.
I think it's asleep.
Wait.
Don't look.
We can't move the rock. we'll be trapped.
Spread the word.
In the morning. when it lets out its flock. we'll rush the entrance.
Pressed up.
I'm gonna kill him.
Go!
It'll notice. but grab the thin end. put it in the fire.
How much rope do we have?
How big's the flock?
A couple dozen. maybe.
That's too many of us.
When it comes back. two of us have to get out.
Or at least get killed.
Run low. through the flock towards the entrance.
and then split wide.
So we can only grab one of them.
Right.
Well. four of us should make the run.
Two and two.
Why risk more than men?
He ate two of us last night.
We're warming up the two before he sleeps.
Go. go. go!
Oh. my God.
No!
What about his body?
What about it?
We just leave him here to rot?
As food for that thing?
We honor our dead Odysseus.
He died helping us escape.
We'll honor him by escaping.
Rage is more pain.
He can talk.
Why didn't it talk before?
Do you talk to ants?
Should we reason with it?
I think we're past that.
I don't think I'm going to be able to make it out of here.
I'm going to have to get out of here.
I'm not sure what's going on here. but I'm pretty sure I'm going to die if I don't do this.
I don't think I'm going to be able to make it.
I don't think I'm going to make it.
What are you doing?
No!
Let's get out of here!
Go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go
When we put its eye out we heard it crying his name that thing was a monster. I heard it. too
So now the seas against us and the wind
Are we supposed to get home with Poseidon against us? We can't live by omens and sacrifices
Do you know how many times I've heard you weeping praying to Athena since we left Troy couldn't you have shown some mercy
Take this
Wear it. to remember those we couldn't bury.
The gods helped those who helped themselves.
From that moment. every rough sea or headwind
told the crew we were cursed.
But where is my crew?
When will you let me see my men?
If I could just talk to them. they'd help me remember.
Did I have a wife. children. maybe a son?
How long have I been here?
A long time.
If I had a son. how old would he be now?
I don't know how to speak to a king.
You'll be fine.
Just keep your mouth shut.
But if anyone asks. we're traitors from Crete.
Then we'll figure out how to approach the king.
Welcome.
Thank you.
You seem to be having quite-
This way.
Where are you taking us?
The King insists on meeting strangers himself.
Sid.
Not you.
Enjoy our hospitality.
It's who's demands.
But perhaps you should tell us who you are.
You picked the right day to arrive.
Feast on my daughter's wedding.
Tomorrow she leaves to start a new life.
You don't look like a beggar.
Imagine you know who I am.
And now last. son of Atreus. brother of Agamemnon. husband of Helen.
Perhaps you've heard of Helen.
Face. I launched a thousand ships.
That may be now just five hundred.
So many left on the battlefields of Troy for that face.
For your brother's ambition.
This one looks familiar.
Hey. Jax.
Chocolates.
Killies.
I don't miss them as much as one particular warrior.
He was the smartest of us all.
Ten years. we brought it on that beach.
We're deadlocked. fighting amongst ourselves until one man.
He found a way.
Modestious.
You ever hear the story of the horse?
What did you hear from the inside. man?
We were in there for days.
We squeezed inside before the ship set sail.
Odysseus. he knew that no one could know that we were inside.
not even sinning the soldier we left behind.
First two tides are men drown right in front of us
They sign up a piss shit
A gift for Athena.
Common gods. respect their offerings.
No. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no
Go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go. go
It's an offering for Athena!
I don't know what's going on here.
He knew to wait for a moonless night around the plains of Troy.
Go!
Get to the gates!
To the gates!
Go!
Go. go!
Whoa!
Come on!
I think you know the rest.
Am I telling it you should hear the bird sing it I have
But they weren't there with all of you with your father Odysseus
You're so like him
When did you last see him joy?
God's granted us a righteous victory righteous
The gods granted our righteous victory. but did not bless our voyages
It took me years to get home. and he didn't.
Some did and wish they hadn't.
Ugh.
Tell him.
Tell him about your brother.
No.
About the fate the gods bestowed on him after your righteous struggle.
About his hero's welcome.
No.
About how Agamemnon made it home years before us.
Tell him how he was welcomed by his queen. my twin sister Clytemnestra.
No.
Tell him how she-
No!
He does not want to hear about my brother!
I once knew of his father.
I know nothing of Odysseus since Troy.
Nothing?
Not from any of your men?
Or Agamemons. or traitors. or travelers?
Did you come here for some reason?
Is that what you're interested in. gossip?
You're in the right place.
Anyone want to spin a story about Odysseus?
Some say he's rich. or some say poor.
Some say he perished. some say he's in prison.
What say you?
In prison?
What kind of prison could hold a man like that?
Tell me what you do. remember.
The rest will come.
The men became more and more convinced
that I'd offended Poseidon.
Go!
We were hit by storm after storm. all pushing us off course. until we were truly lost.
Whoa!
We're here in peace.
We just need some food.
We need food.
Can't you understand that?
It's just a child.
If that's a child. what about its parents?
Hey. shh. it's okay.
No. no. no. no.
Shhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh
Let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go. let's go.
Ah!
Aargh!
Come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on.
Let's go!
Wait!
Go!
Hey! Run. you bastards!
Turn to port. follow the coast.
What if they have ships?
We need to get as far away as possible.
We don't have supplies for a blind crossing.
We've lost our way.
We need to find food and get our bearings.
Turn to port.
There!
Smoke!
Go past!
We'll find the anchorage at the beach!
There!
Where's John?
Form a landing party.
Tomorrow.
Leave someone with the tenders.
We think you should stay.
We?
All of us.
Still alive.
Is this a mutiny?
That's up to you.
Give me your boat.
I'll make sure we eat tonight.
No matter what you find.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
No. no. no. it's okay. it's okay. you're okay. it's all right. no one's going to hurt you.
If I do what you want.
No one is going to hurt you.
My name's Eurylochus.
What's your name?
Cersei.
Cersei. we need food. badly.
I have food. lots of food.
You let me?
Your weapons.
Your armor.
Put it out the back.
Come on. let's go.
You like my meat?
Why?
Do you have so much?
You never know when strangers will come.
It looks like they're appetites.
Too much is never enough.
Oh
No. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no
They haven't come back yet.
None of them?
No.
Give me your dagger.
Stay with the boat.
Let's go.
Why don't you just come here?
Did you come from the sea?
Are you alone?
My pigs have taken a liking to you.
Are you hungry?
Leave your weapons at the door and enjoy the hospitality of Zeus.
Grab a hog. You can slaughter it for your dinner.
Whoever you are. you're clearly not a farmer.
Here.
That stew smells good.
That's enough for just us.
Who says it's just us?
Who else is here?
Who indeed?
You say you're all alone. but no one comes here alone.
No?
You can only reach this spot by sea.
So. where are your shipmates?
I'm looking for them.
Anyone happen to come this way?
But you prepared all this food.
You're questioning me? You?
The Traveler. who's clearly starving.
yet hasn't touched the food in front of him.
claims to be a sailor. yet wears a great warrior's armor.
and who breaks Zeus' law
by bringing a dagger into his hostess's house.
You have sharp eyes.
Sharpened by the gods.
Do they grant you insights?
Truths.
Sometimes.
Would they tell you where I could find my men?
You're a man.
That's right.
I would.
And would you tell me?
Perhaps.
If you give me your dagger.
Why would I help a liar
who refuses my hospitality?
The other men were here earlier.
No. they're not.
They moved on?
Yes.
Leaving their rings.
I would eat them.
Don't!
I don't know who this crow is to you.
If you don't put that knife down.
I will throttle it to find her.
Don't hurt her.
Family.
Mother.
Your sister.
You did this to her like you turned my men into pigs.
I didn't turn your men into anything!
Look at them!
This is who they are! Look at them!
Base. disgusting. criminal urges that you value in battle.
They've raped and pillaged across the world for you.
And you think that's against their nature?
You think they only did that because you ordered them to?
A true commander thinks his men's savagery is actually discipline.
You don't seem that deluded.
But you sent them to me here.
On my own.
A gang of filthy soldiers with empty bellies and hot blood.
You thought they'd respect me and my home?
Look at them!
Know your own men!
Did they hurt you?
They would've.
They just want to go home.
Let them.
Come back.
Back into your disguises.
Back.
Come back.
Back into your disguises.
Back into your disguise.
Come back.
Odysseus. back to the ship.
Take all the food you can carry.
Leave the meat.
You're not gonna let her live. She's a witch.
Who care for powers? You're gods.
Fill the jugs and skins at the stream.
Be ready to sail at dawn.
Why leave her like this?
We get on better this way.
I'm sorry if we offended you.
We can't get back without your help.
We need to know the way to the trade routes.
You're too lost.
What do you mean?
Only blind Teresias can tell you how to go home.
Teresias?
In Hades.
Nobody sails into hell and comes back.
You will.
Head north into the twilight.
And head inland until a river of fire meets a river of ice.
There you must dig a trench and fill it with the blood of sacrifice.
And learn how you go home.
You.
Not your men.
You'd curse them?
Not a curse.
A truth.
Your men don't want you to defy the gods.
The gods say only you make it home.
Then I defy the gods.
Senar. it's Odysseus.
Let him drink Odysseus. then you will hear his testament.
Oh. do you see us?
Yes.
He lied to everyone.
Did you have to lie to me?
I needed you to believe.
Why did you have to volunteer?
Don't you remember how I came here?
I begged to take Antinous' place.
He'd been called.
He offered money for your family
If you take his place.
If the Trojans don't let me live.
if I never make it home.
take this back to my father.
tell him everything I did.
Odysseus.
feel free to add some stuff.
You didn't trust me with the truth?
You knew I'd die for you.
Dying meant tell the truth. I needed you to believe.
I died for your lie on that beach.
I know. I was there with you.
I heard you repeat the lie with your dying breath.
winning us the war.
I was right there. inches from you. smelling your blood.
What comfort could that give me?
Not knowing you were beside that horse until the dead told me.
Which dead?
A lot of veterans of your campaigns walk these shores.
The dead meet to lament the living and greet the newly dead.
My father was the first shade to find me.
To comfort you.
Shades don't comfort.
They want word of the living who wronged them.
My father had died in poverty. alone.
Begging for scraps from people like Antinous.
Antinous cheated you?
As he's no doubt cheating you.
How?
Who's in Ithaca looking after your wife and son?
My wife is of no concern.
Talk to Agamemnon about homecomings.
Agamemnon's here?
You buried me at Troy with respect. thank you.
But spare a thought for those who didn't.
It's not always possible.
When you get home.
take a ship. head into the unknown west
till you find land.
and there give sacrifice and honor your men.
Do you still have the lot?
Of course.
If you make it home. give Antinous back his shame.
I will.
Come on.
My lord.
Odysseus.
How are you here?
We won the war. you're headed for home.
Odysseus. the most brilliant of all my generals.
He would never be snared as I was.
When you cast the drift. like us.
No. My misfortune was to make it home.
Be welcomed by my beautiful wife.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Oh. no.
She and her lover had plotted my murder for years.
Odysseus.
Yes.
My son Orestes.
Did he avenge me?
My lord. how could I know?
I'm still trying to get home.
Don't make my mistake.
Don't walk in the front door expecting garlands and praise.
Come in disguise.
Take your time.
Assess.
Do you see?
I know what I have to do.
Some of what you have to do.
My prophecy is not for their ears.
Back to the ship.
Sail southwest.
Past the sirens.
Their song lures your men onto the rocks.
They all die.
I won't let that happen.
I'll block their ears with wax.
Past the sirens.
You choose between the whirlpool Charybdis and the monster Scylla.
The whirlpool in the sea takes all of your lives.
The monster in the cliffs? Only six.
But your determination to not sacrifice any more lives kills all of them.
I'll do what I have to.
At the end. when starvation and mutiny threaten. they demand to land where the Sun God grazes his cattle.
They slaughter Apollo's herd.
Zeus kills them for it.
Do you see?
I'll stop them.
Why do you value these men's lives more than those you've already lost?
I can still save them from the gods.
But not from themselves.
What is that?
Your unburied crew
Demanding you share their dishonor
Go away!
He's out!
We rode out of hell. leaving so many fallen comrades.
I have to save the rest.
What's happened to them?
Did they leave me here?
Are they coming back?
Did you do something to them?
How so?
You told me not to eat the lotus flower.
Just tonight.
So you can get some sleep.
And tomorrow. when you're ready.
You'll remember.
You'll remember your crew.
And your family.
Family?
A wife?
Do I have a wife?
It's alright. Melantho.
Strangers don't come in here.
Screen or no screen. after three years of feasting together. we're far from strangers. Melanie.
Are you trying to marry me or ruin my reputation?
Milanto can be discreet.
I'm actually here out of concern for your reputation.
Oh?
Everyone sees how hard you work.
Slow. steady progress.
Mm.
But every night. you've been unraveling that work.
Leave us.
You can't expect her to be loyal to a master
she never even knew.
I expect her to be loyal to me.
And she will be. when you're married to me.
Slaves have no choice but to be loyal to the future.
And this is a household waiting for a master.
just as Ethika is a kingdom waiting for a king.
Ethika's king is coming back.
No. he's not.
Do you know that as a boy. I tried to go with him to Troy?
He never told me that.
Dizzy's refused to let me.
He knew that Ithaca needed a future without him.
And he saw me as part of that future.
I'll never tell other suitors about your...
deception.
Finish your weaving.
It's time to let him go.
Why would you want to marry someone who loves someone else?
Your loyalty to Odysseus is one of your finest qualities.
I love you.
I want you to choose me
can end all this.
You can't tell me you're not tired. the waiting.
the uncertainty.
You've done your duty year after year after year.
It's time to think of yourself.
It's time to live again.
It's what Odysseus would have wanted.
I'll take care of all your needs.
My queen.
And my son?
The throne is his.
He's the heir.
Unless we have a child of our own.
Where is Telemachus?
He's gone inland to visit his grandfather.
She's lying. he's going to see.
It's gone from here to his father.
Where?
He's gone to Sparta.
To Menelaus.
Well. should we go there?
No.
Move out. Melanthius.
I told you. you're a coward.
He was listening.
No. no.
I was coming for Argus.
I told you that dog stays there.
Go back to the farm.
When we need your pigs. we'll send Melanthius.
You're no longer welcome in this palace. old man.
I answered to my mistress.
Does she even know your name?
Now. go.
Telemachus will have to come back by the temple at Pylos.
You take your man away from there.
Well. he can stay and try and charm the queen.
I don't think so.
He needs to die on that road.
And Iris has a plan.
Iris!
I need everyone in this party dead in a ditch.
Throat's open.
Telemachus and his men will be ready for the bandits
who work the road between here and Pylos.
But if some of them took the temple from the priests
before they arrived...
Then bring me part of Telemachus' proof.
His nose.
Would you know him only by his nose?
His ears. too.
Looked out for you.
My father's swineherd.
Swineherd?
As most loyal servant.
Odysseus left his most loyal servant behind.
He always was the smartest.
Only one Agamemnon ever listened to.
Should have listened harder.
Can I ask what happened to your brother?
His wife betrayed him.
Murdered him.
What did you do to him?
His son Orestes.
He killed them both.
But he killed his own mother?
He avenged his father.
But you don't have to worry.
Your mother has nothing in common with Clytemnestra.
Maybe not.
But the suitors have convinced the elders
it's time she remarried.
Yeah. it's not a good time for an empty throne.
I've heard the stories. people from the sea.
Have you been raided?
Not yet. but the attacks. they do seem closer.
Sparta's ready.
What about Ithaca?
She'd be able to raise an army. defend herself.
Someone's got to take the throne.
Then the battle is there. not here. son.
You've run from the problem.
Left your mother. the mercy of the suitors.
Should I hire mercenaries. go back and kill them all?
Murder rich and powerful guests in your own home.
You'd be exiled.
What then?
You must evict them without violating Zeus's law.
I have to take the throne.
I have to know if Odysseus is alive.
This has nothing to do with a father you've never known.
You have to lead. son.
No matter what's happened to Odysseus.
You need to remember.
No. I don't.
I don't need to know the truth.
I'm happy here with you.
Why are you gathering the bones of your old ship
to make a raft?
Remember your crew.
Your journey.
I heard the song of the sirens.
Put the wax in the men's ears.
Not for me.
Tie me to the mast.
Why?
I want to hear the siren song.
No. that's a bad idea.
No one's ever heard the song in a lib.
That's why it's a good idea.
I'll be the first.
No matter how hard I plead. do not untie me
until we're well clear.
Check the men's ears.
A week's rations for the first. yes. sir!
Oh
What was the siren's song?
All the things he wanted to be. then all the things he wished he never wished for.
It was the delicious itch you go to scratch to find it's under the skin you can't reach
So. the delicious edge becomes unbearable.
Told you what you most want is what you most can't have.
And what you most can't have is what you already had and lost.
It was the song of all the promises I failed to keep.
And it told me I don't really want to go home.
My water!
My water ahead!
Charybdis.
A monstrous whirlpool.
Hoist the sails!
Come on. let's go!
Get the winds. let's go!
Let me head out to sea.
Somebody got us.
Get in the group!
We want to have roots moving!
We might make that canyon.
It's too narrow.
Make for the whirlpool.
If you steer down the slope.
we can make enough way to shoot out the other side.
Don't be afraid. We can do it.
No. No!
We're making for the channel.
We're making for the channel!
Origin!
Get the origin!
It's over yours!
Prepare to hold water!
On my signal!
Three. two. one. four. four. three. two. one. two. three. two. one. four. three. two.
No!
We made it!
We did it!
You guys...
Keep us straight!
You knew! And you didn't tell us!
If I told you. you wouldn't have chosen this way.
And those men would still be alive!
No! We'd all be dead!
You had no right!
I had every right.
And every responsibility.
The whirlpool would have destroyed the ship and all of us.
This way we'd live.
Some of us live!
Yes!
What else did Tiresias tell you?
I'm going to put in there.
We can't land there.
That's the Sun God's Isle.
We need repairs.
These men are exhausted.
We lost six shipments.
We're going to put in.
We're going to rest up on dry land.
You're all going to die.
You asked me what Teresa has told me.
He said you're all going to die.
If you slaughter the sun god's cattle which graze on that island. you'll all die.
That's fine. We'll put in. we'll cook our own provisions. we'll pick fruit. we'll get water. nothing more.
Swear to it. all of you.
We'll rest up. do the repairs. and set out as soon as the wind changes.
Grab that line.
Did the crew keep their promise?
Yes. For a long time.
But the wind never changed.
The steady onshore breeze that made it so easy for us to land
and made it impossible to leave.
And our provisions ran out.
Go!
Did you think if you ate quietly. the sun god wouldn't notice?
We thought you wouldn't notice.
I'm not the problem.
I wanted you to live.
I see consequence. I see my failure.
What if their deaths aren't your failure. but theirs?
I lead them.
I led them here.
And who led you?
Why do you put yourself above the gods?
Why do you claim responsibility?
Why don't you want to go home?
What do you expect?
They ran out of food.
Have some pity.
My pity is what put us on this damn island.
I told you what would happen.
Yes. you did.
And we decided we would rather drown than starve.
Well. now's our chance.
The wind has dropped!
The calm was just long enough to lure us
out onto Poseidon's ocean. under Zeus's sky.
Come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come
Oh. my God!
Get your guns to the guns!
Pray for Poseidon!
Pray for freaking this!
No. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no
hand of Zeus.
I don't know what happened to my men yes you do exactly what you told them what
happened I washed up on your shore alone you
You washed up on my shore with some of your boat
and none of your crew. half-dead. unconscious.
I watched you lost for days and two weeks.
I knew the lotus would ease your awakening.
so that your pain was more of the body than the mind.
And it did.
You liked it so much.
You ate it so willingly.
And as I cared for you.
I came to love you.
How long have I been here?
I kept telling myself to stop giving it to you.
that you were strong enough to remember.
How long. Calypso?
You were so happy.
You were happy.
We were so happy.
For years.
Years?
Seven years.
You fed me lotus flower and held me captive.
I saved your life.
I rebuilt your body.
I just couldn't bring myself to rebuild your mind.
You have been happy.
Your heart was just always somewhere else.
And your mind was bound to follow eventually.
How could you?
The lotus clouds the mind and sops the well.
but it doesn't change who you are.
You weren't ready to go home for whatever reason.
I am now.
As I always knew you would be.
How?
You were clutching something when I found you.
Your hand wouldn't open for weeks.
You'd call out.
Mostly to Athena. but sometimes you would say another name.
Can you help me?
Help me go home.
I am.
You're a man who needs to control his fate.
but you cannot control this.
You must give yourself to the storm.
give yourself to Poseidon.
and take your punishment.
Zeus won't let him kill you.
Give up the fight. give up control.
and live. it's a leap of faith you've never yet made. Odysseus.
The
Odysseus.
Where am I?
Don't you recognize your own home?
I don't know what to do with you.
Zeus welcomes you strangers.
How many are you?
Half a dozen.
Need of a meal?
And supplies for the road.
Where are you headed?
We need pigs.
We're going all the way to Pylos.
Are you pilgrims?
Do we look like pilgrims?
I don't see well.
It's just a man's hour for you a meal.
but these pigs aren't mine to sell.
Oh don't worry.
We're not paying.
Give my greetings to your mother
Sorry. I'm sorry for Troy and for everything that has happened in my name
So I had no news of your father no you had news not of where he is. but who he is
And now more than ever I hope to one day media
Where are your watchdogs. old man?
I'm burning their bodies.
Can Zeus offer you food and drink. stranger?
Were you attacked?
The dog saved your farmhands.
Oh. he burned his brothers first.
What's happened to Ithaca?
Darkness. Ziz's law smashed to pieces.
A kingdom without a king since my master died.
Your master.
Odysseus.
Hero of the Trojan War.
But Odysseus is alive.
Bigger is ever-falling hope!
No more! No more! No more!
No more! No more! No more! No more!
Telemachus.
Telemachus. Telemachus.
He's in danger. and I can't help him.
There must be others in Yessica that would help Odysseus' son.
Paris is controlled by suitors.
No one's still loyal to Odysseus.
What about the queen?
Beautiful wife Penelope.
held hostage by the worst men.
soon to be forced into marriage.
What could she do without even her son?
Here. drink.
What's the danger to Telemachus?
He's on his way back from Spartan.
The suitors sent Bantas to Pylos
to ambush him at the temple.
Give me food for the road.
You'll never catch up with the Bantas.
If I can get to Pylos before Telemachus arrives.
I can warn him.
Why are you helping?
If I tell you. don't be angry.
I served with Odysseus at Troy.
Really?
He was a harsh taskmaster.
Oh. but fair.
Fair and worthy of following.
You loved him.
Like a son.
Well. he's not dead.
Is he coming home?
Soon.
Bringing vengeance?
It's... bringing it all.
I'll talk you don't want people realizing where you are well maybe we
shouldn't have brought a guard we'll be glad we did if we have trouble on the
road
I have a message.
Wait!
You may have sent me.
Find that beggar.
Your men must wait out here.
The weapons. too.
Zeus welcomes you. strangers.
Have you traveled far?
Not that far.
You're here to rest for the night.
We're here to make sacrifice to Athena.
And whatever hospitality you can offer might be considered.
Of course. Get that beggar out of here.
He has a message for me.
You may have sent you.
Yes. sir.
Well. what's the message?
It's private.
These men are pri...
This is your moment to leave old man go stranger
I already spared one old man this week. but he was blind. I won't spare
Let's go.
It's not bad for a beggar.
No one's born a beggar.
We'll take these priest robes. put them over your armor.
Help me with his body.
We have to leave him.
No.
We have to slip out.
That's not how you honor the dead.
That is how you stay alive.
He was my teacher.
He might have been Athena in disguise.
His name was Mentor.
And when you are safe. we'll travel to the unknown West.
and we will honor him.
These men were sent by the suitors.
There will be more of them than we need to get on the road.
By night?
Safer than staying here.
Mantra's at the heart of Athena's oldest temple.
For now. we'll honor him in flame.
Come on. let's get out of here.
Come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come
I'm an old soldier who fought under your father at Troy.
He knew my father?
I've been taking orders from him for longer
than I care to remember.
Wait. he's alive?
He's alive.
Well. where is he?
He's close by.
He sent me ahead to assess the situation.
Well. Mother's not going to believe.
No. you can't tell her.
What. nothing?
Tell her. tell her he decided it's time she remarried.
He doesn't need to test my mother. How can he doubt her?
He doesn't. but she has every reason to have forgotten him.
Are there any loyal servants?
Some.
Well. at this he shows himself off.
We need to gather the suitors at the palace.
That's never a problem.
You have gifts for Menelaus?
Yeah. on my ship.
Good.
Come back as a prince. Call a banquet.
I'll be there.
What will you do at the banquet?
Beg.
The clearest view of a man is from below.
How many suitors are there?
Dozens.
If all of his men are like you. then...
He doesn't have any men.
What. it's just you?
And you.
Telemachus is back.
What?
Who's saying this?
Everyone's saying that.
Where's Telemachus?
My queen!
Charming Herod's place is up there.
Is it true?
I thought tonight we could celebrate if we have anything left to celebrate with.
Don't worry.
My brave suitors will shower us with gifts to honor your return.
So glad to see your safe return.
I'm glad to see you on your feet.
It's about time we took you back to the palace.
What did you hear about your father?
Nothing.
Stories from the war. but no one
knew what happened to him after he left Troy.
I'm sorry. Mom.
Everyone in Sparta is talking about a coming catastrophe.
an age of darkness brought on by people from the sea
violating Zeus' law.
Those stories are true. Our civilization is collapsing.
Menelaus is concerned that we can't raise an army
with an empty throne. so we came up with a plan.
What plan?
The one way to get the Surtis to leave.
It's time for you to choose.
You want me to remarry?
If you remarry. the other suitors will leave.
and then I'm only dealing with one of them.
I'm almost of age. I'll tell the elders
that I learned of Odysseus' death in Sparta.
Menelaus will back me up.
and they'll let me assume the throne.
So you deny your father. and I leave my home
and go and live with one of these snakes.
That's your plan.
Would you have a better one?
Lock the door. set a fire. and burn the bastards.
Do you think if I remarry. life goes back to the way it was?
That world is gone. and in this one.
they're not giving up power to you or Odysseus.
If he returned. he'd have to kill him. like you will.
If I kill them. their families will demand revenge.
I'd be exiled.
And without me. the throne will be lost.
Because only a man can sit on it.
Empty throne?
I've been sitting on that empty throne for 20 years.
My knowledge. my years of experience.
that's all nothing compared with the bristles on your chin.
Do you want peace?
Or do you want revenge?
I want Odysseus!
Scene!
Muse of a face!
A face!
a fleet. a war. at Troy. sing news of a man. a man.
Let's go.
You should bury him up on the cliff.
Where you met.
You're Odysseus.
You're my father.
I'm a beggar.
And you...
You are the worthy. beautiful son of Odysseus.
of whom. when you do finally meet. he will be so proud.
Well. come on. stranger.
Because the darkness of victory
shrouds the right as the legends.
and make boys the blind beggars of us all!
Accept the hospitality of Zeus.
Get the strangers some food.
No. sir.
I'll just make the rounds with a bowl.
Had to invite another one of these filthy plate lickers today?
What's one more beggar at this feast?
We need to kill him before he ever gains his position with the elders.
Oh
Broken get him to grab one of the weapons
He's not the same young pup we used to be you come back tonight
Let me cut his tongue.
Fuck off. old man.
Please. It's been days since I've eaten.
I told you to fuck off.
You can't be generous with food that's not even yours.
There's no room in your bowl.
Yes. there is.
So there is.
There you go.
I suppose you want something from me now no I have something for you you have
something from me what could a filthy old plate liquor like you possibly have
that I could want actually it's yours
I was asked to return it.
It's not mine.
No?
Well. where did you get this?
Don't turn your back on me!
Continuous.
You can't treat a beggar like that.
It's Zeus's law.
Zeus's law.
You think this is a guard?
You think this is a guard in disguise?
Are you?
Are you a guard?
Whitenecker?
No.
I'm a veteran of the Trojan War.
Veteran of the Trojan War.
And what's your name. veteran?
I don't remember that.
Yeah. yeah.
He wanted you to take his place.
Where did he go?
Where he'll soon be. and where is that?
Hey. Deez.
Enough!
The feast is done!
The skull is not mine!
A queen would like to speak with you.
Stay till everyone's left and the fire's over.
Hello. Traveler.
My queen.
Melantho. have your clay wash the stranger's feet.
That's not necessary.
My husband insisted we honor guests as family.
You know of Odysseus. my husband?
Of course.
Who are the songs?
I was at Troy. ma'am.
The songs probably seem silly.
They make me cry.
Why?
For what was lost.
The lives?
And the years.
Everything.
Did you know I'd just see us at Troy?
I did.
Was there some detail
of how he dressed. something he wore?
He wore a strange pin.
Strange?
Beautiful.
But out of place.
Describe it.
I'll get more water.
It was a beautiful gold pen.
A figure of Athena encircled by vines.
Did he wear it off?
He never took it off.
How is it that you made it home when Odysseus could not?
I'm not home.
Not yet.
Why not?
It's not always an easy thing. a homecoming.
That's as true for Odysseus as for me.
The Odysseus I knew would have found
or fought his way back to me no matter what.
What if the Odysseus you knew lost his way?
What if one night in a strange city
He saw things that made him think the home he knew
couldn't possibly be there anymore.
What if. when he left the belly of the horse
and opened the gates of Troy.
He saw ten years of rage pour into that city in one night.
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááá
No!
We left them a gift. an offering of peace that they took into their home.
We violated all that's ever sacred between people and turned a viper into a hunt.
No. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no
What if he knew
That very night
As he walked through fires of anarchy and pain
and in the days of sweaty celebrations to follow.
What if he knew exactly what he'd done?
What all of you had done.
One man's idea.
One man's trick.
To break Zeus' law forever.
We lived in a world of palaces and trade.
And language. blind to its beauty.
Until we broke it.
You are the people from the sea.
Yes. my queen.
The breaking of Zeus' law is spreading. and I plague.
Our age of bronze is collapsing.
and maybe he couldn't bear to see the ruins of what he'd done anywhere.
Least of all. his home.
But Odysseus is alive.
And he'll be here when you need him most.
Wow.
I've been living in his ruins long enough.
Bring the suitors at dawn.
Remove the arms from the hall.
In a few hours. one suitor will be happy.
And the rest. angry vengeful men.
Rons draws a man on. so we'll have no weapons at the trial.
and the doors will be locked.
I'll marry whoever completes my challenge.
How will we take on the suitors?
Not we.
Their blood belongs on my hands.
Or you'd face exile.
Won't you?
Just make sure they can't get those weapons.
I'll see to it.
Even an arm. there are so many of them.
And you won't have a weapon.
Oh. I'll have a weapon.
Your mother's seen to that.
Gather the servants you trust.
Lock the arms in the upper storage room.
Hurry. hurry. give me one of those guys.
Hurry. hurry. hurry.
I don't know what's going on.
I don't know.
Let's try it.
For years. while my husband's been gone.
You've commandeered this palace for your feasting.
Your excuse was. you wanted to win my hand in marriage.
As I listen to you party.
you fight. corrupt my servants.
and disrespect my home?
I've wanted nothing more than for Odysseus to return
and see all this for himself.
But last night. I realized he's not here now.
He never will be.
So. I stand ready to marry anyone here who can string this hunting bow
and shoot an arrow through those twelve axes.
Step up.
And show me who you are.
Eumaeus.
Who's first?
Give me the bow.
Mm!
Ah!
Oh. this bow hasn't been strung in years.
Ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha
Now. your turn.
There's no need.
The Queen has made her point.
We can't replace Odysseus.
Some of us have always known that.
Some of us would have followed that great man.
Detroit. if he'd let us.
But he never came back.
So choose the best of us here.
All of us who failed your test.
I haven't.
Somebody get these beggars out of here!
The doors are locked until the trial's over.
The trial is over.
I want to try.
Give it a rest!
He has a right to try.
If he won't. he may as well.
You're making a mockery of your mother's wishes.
My mother's wishes are for you all to burn.
He's an old archer.
Look at the expert at work.
Wait right here!
Come on!
Oh. old man. forget it!
Okay. friend. Friend. that's enough.
Oh. let him go!
Oh
What's that?
You're dizzy.
Oh!
Surely your place is down there.
Is it him?
It's him!
Stop securing the weapons!
Where are the weapons?
They're in the upper store room.
Get them!
You waste work!
You're gonna kill us all!
Look out!
I told you. too loud cowherd!
Down!
Let's go. let's go!
Get the doors!
Oh. shit!
Come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come on. come
I thought you could kill us all.
How long does that kill you?
Finish this.
Get him!
When you get to Hades. tell my men I will head west and honor them.
Then tell Senna. I give you back your shame.
What happened?
Did he beat them?
Is he dead?
We broke the fragile bonds between men.
And for centuries of darkness to follow.
the stories of Troy will only be sung.
No. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no. no.
To see my beloved. if I could one last time.
No.
No. no. no.
You can't.
Not now.
Please.
It's over.
You can't die.
Not death.
Exile.
We'll head into the unknown west to honor my men... together.
Take your fastest ship and greatest crew and head for the horizon.
Chasing the escaping sun.
Why will the stories only be sung?
Because songs will be all they have to remember those of us who could write.
Civilization will rise again.
A new dawn will break over the darkened world. and our mistakes will once again be forgotten.